Register of the Fred M. Hechinger Papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Fred M. Hechinger Papers
1937-1991
89019
Hechinger, Fred M.
74 manuscript boxes, 8 oversize boxes. (32.8 linear feet)
Hoover Institution on War, Revolution, and Peace Stanford, California 94305-6010
A noted American journalist and education editor, the collection includes speeches and writings, correspondence, reviews, memoranda, studies, scrapbooks, and printed matter, all relating to education in the United States.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1989.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog Socrates at http://library.stanford.edu/webcat. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in Socrates is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Chronology
1920 July 7 Born, Nuremberg, Germany
1943 Naturalized; A.B., City College, New York
1944-1946 Member, Office of Military Attach, American Embassy, and with British War Office
1945 Graduate study, University of London
1946-1947 Correspondent, Times Educational Supplement, London
1947-1950 Education Editor and Foreign Correspondent, Bridgeport Sunday Herald Education Columnist, Washington Post
1948 Special Consultant to the Director, Education and Cultural Relations Division, U.S. Military Government in Germany
1948-1950 Foreign Correspondent, Overseas News Agency
1950-1956 Education Editor, New York Herald Tribune
1956 Author, An Adventure in Education: Connecticut Points the Way
1956-1959 Associate Publisher and Executive Editor, Bridgeport Sunday Herald
1958 Married Grace Bernstein. Author, Worrying About College?
1959 Author, The Big Red Schoolhouse
1959-1969 Education Editor, New York Times
1963 Author, Teen-Age Tyranny (with Grace Hechinger)
1968 Author, New York Times Guide to New York City Private Schools (with Grace Hechinger)
1969-1977 Member, Editorial Board, New York Times
1973- Adjunct professor, Hunter College and Queens College, City University of New York
1975 Author, Growing Up in America (with Grace Hechinger)
1976 Assistant Editor, editorial page, New York Times
1976-1977 Deputy Editor, editorial page, New York Times
1977-1990 President, New York Times Company Foundation
1981 Author, Higher Learning in the Nation's Service(with Ernest L. Boyer)
1988-1995 Member and Vice Chairman, Board of Trustees, and Senior Advisor, Carnegie Corporation of New York
1992 Author, Fateful Choices: Healthy Youth for the 21st Century
1995 November 6 Died, New York
Scope and Content of Collection
The papers of Fred M. Hechinger, a noted journalist and expert in the field of education, are an important addition to the education collections already in the Hoover Institution Archives. They will constitute a significant source of information for students and researchers interested in the issues relating to education in the United States, from kindergarten to the college level. Fred Hechinger along with his wife, Grace Hechinger, also an author and champion of the cause of literacy, devoted a significant part of his life to writing about education, and the causes of its decline in the United States, and suggesting ways to improve it. His contributions were recognized by many educational institutions, as evident in the number of honorary degrees bestowed upon him.
The correspondence series represents Fred Hechinger's interaction with many individuals and organizations on questions of education. His opinions and observations about their research and publications were always sought after. The speeches and writings series testifies to his genuine interest and devotion to the cause of education. He was flooded with invitations to write, speak, and be interviewed. The comments and reviews of his speeches and writings bear out the level of expertise he acquired and the appreciation and acknowledgements he received from grateful fellow educators and parents. This series also includes writings jointly completed by Fred and Grace Hechinger and indicates the prominent role she played in her husband's career.
Fred Hechinger's association with various newspapers and specially with the New York Times as education ed., member of the editorial board, and finally as the president of the New York Times Foundation, is illustrated in the newspaper columns series and the New York Times and New York Times Foundation series. Together, they reveal his level of involvement in the newspaper and the role he played in the organization, the columns he wrote, the ideas and suggestions he received from his friends, admirers, and the public, and their opinions about his columns. The career file includes records of his association with different organizations and is indicative of the high regard in which he was held by his peers.
The papers of Grace Hechinger, found in a separate series, although not large in volume, are nevertheless significant, as they reflect her own interest in educational issues. Besides biographical material and correspondence, the series provides samples of her writings.
Arrangement
Arranged into twelve series: Biographical File, Correspondence, Speeches and Writings, Newspaper Columns File, New York Times and New York Times Foundation File, Career File, Grace Hechinger File, Subject File, Photographs, Computer Disk, Oversize File, and Scrapbooks.
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
Subjects
Education--United States.
Occupations
Journalists.
Container List
- Biographical File, 1937-1990.; See also Oversize File and Scrapbooks
  Biographical sketches, certificates, clippings and printed matter, press card, student papers, subject file, and miscellany, arranged alphabetically by physical form.
  - Biographical sketches (Folder 1: 1)
  - Certificates (Folder 1: 2)
  - Clippings and printed matter about Fred Hechinger (Folder 1: 3)
  - Press card, 1948. (Folder 1: 4)
    Includes photograph
  - Student papers by Fred Hechinger.
    Typescript
    - "Eight Weeks in America," MAGPIE, undated (Folder 1: 5)
    - "First Impressions on Paradox," Paradoxian, 1937. (Folder 1: 6)
      Includes a sketch of a boat in a river by Fred Hechinger
    - "Paradoxian,", 1938 (Folder 1: 7)
    - "Thoughts on Charles Lamb," 1939 Spring; "The Origins, Thoughts, and Practices of Fascism," 1940; "The Nature of Writing History," 1940 January; "As Truth Will Paint It: A Critical Review of Hamlin Garland's Son of the Middle Border," 1940 Spring; "Literary Photography: A Critical Review of Sinclair Lewis' Main Street," 1940 Spring; "Prophet of Doom: A Critical Review of Theodore Dreiser's Sister Carrie," 1940 Spring; "The Red Sickness of Battle: A Critical Review of Stephen Crane's The Red Badge of Courage," 1940 Spring; "Revolt and Tragedy: A Critical Review of Mrs. Edith Wharton's Ethan Frome," 1940 Spring; "The Positive Side of Thomas Paine," 1941? "Edwin Arlington Robinson, Poet and Philosopher: A Critical Discussion," 1941; "Mysticism in Disguise: A Comparison of Rousseau's and Nietzsche's Superman," 1941; "George Chapman's Earliest Extant Play: The Blind Beggar of Alexandria, Discussion," 1942; "The Voice of Disillusion: Echo of Hope, A Critical Discussion of Bertrand Russell's 'Power'," (Folder 1: 8)
  - Subject file
    - Awards (Folder 1: 9)
    - Fellowships (Folder 1: 10)
    - Honorary degrees, including with Grace Hechinger (Folder 1: 11)
    - Medals (Folder 1: 12)
    - Memberships of various organizations (Folder 1: 13)
  - Miscellany (Box-folder 2: 1)
- Correspondence, 1955-1991.
  Letters sent and received by Fred Hechinger, arranged alphabetically by name of correspondent. Includes related materials
  - General
    - General
      - Curricula vitae sent by others (Folder 2: 2)
      - Invitations declined
        - 1967-1979 (Folder 2: 3)
        - 1980-1985 (Folder 2: 4)
        - 1986-1990 (Folder 2: 5)
    - A (Folder 2: 6)
    - B (Box-folder 3: 1)
    - Cam-Cen (Folder 3: 2)
    - Cha-Coll (Folder 3: 3)
    - Comm-Cro (Folder 3: 4)
    - D (Folder 3: 5)
    - Eb-Els (Box-folder 4: 1)
    - Em-Et (Folder 4: 2)
    - F (Folder 4: 3)
    - G (Folder 4: 4)
    - Hah-Hav (Folder 4: 5)
    - Hea-Hya (Folder 4: 6)
    - I-J (Box-folder 5: 1)
    - Kah-Kurz (Folder 5: 2)
    - Lak-Ly (Folder 5: 3)
    - Mac-Mess (Folder 5: 4)
    - Mi-Mu (Folder 5: 5)
    - N (Box-folder 6: 1)
    - O-Perl (Folder 6: 2)
    - Perp-Pub (Folder 6: 3)
    - Ra-Reh (Folder 6: 4)
    - Rei-Ru (Folder 6: 5)
    - Sai-Sha (Box-folder 7: 1)
    - Sib-Sta (Folder 7: 2)
    - Ste-Sz (Folder 7: 3)
    - T (Folder 7: 4)
    - U-V (Folder 7: 5)
    - W-Z (Folder 7: 6)
  - Abram, Morris B., 1984-1985 (Box-folder 8: 1)
  - Abramowitz, Elizabeth A., 1978 (Folder 8: 2)
  - Acer, Charlotte, C., 1988-1990 (Folder 8: 3)
  - Adler, Mortimer J., 1981 (Folder 8: 4)
  - Aetna Life Insurance Company, 1984-1985 (Folder 8: 5)
  - Alter, Joseph, 1955-1986 (Folder 8: 6)
  - American Association for the Advancement of the Humanities, 1980 (Folder 8: 7)
  - American Association of University Professors, 1978-1984 (Folder 8: 8)
  - American Broadcasting Companies, Inc., 1978-1984 (Folder 8: 9)
  - American Heritage Publishing Company, Inc., 1985 (Folder 8: 10)
  - American Humanics, Inc., 1984 (Folder 8: 11)
  - American Institute for Research in the Behavioral Sciences, 1982 (Folder 8: 12)
  - American Reading Council, 1984 (Folder 8: 13)
  - Anderson, Clifford D., 1981-1982 (Folder 8: 14)
  - Arizona. Dept. of Education, 1980-1983 (Folder 8: 15)
  - Arricale, Frank C., II, 1976 (Folder 8: 16)
  - Association of Flat Grant School Districts of New York State, 1981 (Folder 8: 17)
  - Association of Governing Boards of Universities and Colleges, 1978-1991 (Folder 8: 18)
  - AT&T Foundation, 1986 (Folder 8: 19)
  - Bailey, Foster, 1977 (Folder 8: 20)
  - Ballou, Barbara, 1980 (Folder 8: 21)
  - Bard College, 1969-1984 (Folder 8: 22)
  - Barnard College, Columbia University, 1978-1990 (Folder 8: 23)
  - Bennett, William J., 1981 (Folder 8: 24)
  - Bergenn, Victor W., 1984 (Folder 8: 25)
  - Biagi, Shirley, 1978 (Folder 8: 26)
  - Biological Sciences Curriculum Study (BSCS), 1982 (Folder 8: 27)
  - Boone, Geraldine L., 1985 (Folder 8: 28)
  - Boyer, Ernest L., 1976-1988 (Folder 8: 29)
  - Bradford College, 1982 (Folder 8: 30)
  - Bradshaw, Thornton F., 1981 (Folder 8: 31)
  - Brooks, Dick, 1977 (Folder 8: 32)
  - Bush, Barbara, 1989 (Folder 8: 33)
  - Bush, Robert N., 1960-1977 (Folder 8: 34)
  - Butts, R. Freeman, 1979 (Folder 8: 35)
  - Buxton School, 1980 (Folder 8: 36)
  - California. Dept. of Education, 1983 (Folder 8: 37)
  - California. Senate, 1990 (Folder 8: 38)
  - Carnegie Council on Policy Studies in Higher Education, 1980 (Folder 8: 39)
  - Carnegie-Mellon University, 1982 (Box-folder 9: 1)
  - Carnicelli, Thomas, 1977 (Folder 9: 2)
  - Carter, Jimmy and Rosalyn, undated (Folder 9: 3)
  - CBS, Inc., 1984 (Folder 9: 4)
  - Center for Advanced Study in the Behavioral Sciences, 1978 (Folder 9: 5)
  - Change, 1978-1981 (Folder 9: 6)
  - Charles F. Kettering Foundation, 1979-1980. (Folder 9: 7)
    Includes comments by Fred Hechinger
  - Chase Manhattan Bank Foundation, 1971. (Folder 9: 8)
    Includes memorandum by Fred Hechinger
  - Cheek, George C., 1977 (Folder 9: 9)
  - Chemical Bank, 1984 (Folder 9: 10)
  - Citizen Bee, 1986 (Folder 9: 11)
  - City University of New York, 1979-1991 (Folder 9: 12)
  - City University of New York. City College, 1968-1987 (Folder 9: 13)
  - Clark, Ruth, 1976 (Folder 9: 14)
  - Clement, Stephen M., III, 1984 (Folder 9: 15)
  - Cleveland, Harlan, 1977 (Folder 9: 16)
  - Cohen, Herbert L., 1976 (Folder 9: 17)
  - Cohen, Lee, 1977 (Folder 9: 18)
  - Cohen, Martin, 1986-1987 (Folder 9: 19)
  - Cohodes, Aaron, 1986 (Folder 9: 20)
  - Colangelo, Michael, 1977-1978 (Folder 9: 21)
  - College of Arts and Science at Plattsburgh, 1978 (Folder 9: 22)
  - College Board, 1980-1987 (Folder 9: 23)
  - Colorado College, 1979-1981 (Folder 9: 24)
  - Columbia University, 1983-1990 (Folder 9: 25)
  - Columbia University. Teachers College, 1969-1990 (Folder 9: 26)
  - Conservation of Human Resources, 1981-1982 (Folder 9: 27)
  - Cort, Robert P., 1976 (Folder 9: 28)
  - Council for Basic Education, 1979-1981 (Folder 9: 29)
  - Cousins, Norman, 1976 (Folder 9: 30)
  - Crimmins, James C., 1984 (Folder 9: 31)
  - Crown Publishers, Inc., 1978 (Folder 9: 32)
  - Cumberland College, 1990 (Folder 9: 33)
  - Cummings, William K., 1977 (Folder 9: 34)
  - Cunningham, Mara Lemanis, 1977 (Folder 9: 35)
  - Curwood, Steve, 1986 (Folder 9: 36)
  - Dartmouth College, 1979-1987 (Folder 9: 37)
  - Daube, Jonathan M., 1977 (Box-folder 10: 1)
  - Davidoff, Linda, 1976 (Folder 10: 2)
  - Dean, William J., 1979 (Folder 10: 3)
  - Domestic Policy Association, 1982 (Folder 10: 4)
  - Donegan, Jere, 1976 (Folder 10: 5)
  - Douglass College, 1981 (Folder 10: 6)
  - Earthwatch, 1983 (Folder 10: 7)
  - Education Commission of the States (ECS), 1981-1987 (Folder 10: 8)
  - Education USA Newsline, 1983 (Folder 10: 9)
  - Education Week, 1981-1986 (Folder 10: 10)
  - Educational Testing Service, 1980-1990 (Folder 10: 11)
  - Elementary School Study Group, 1985 (Folder 10: 12)
  - Elliott, Frank N., 1983-1984 (Folder 10: 13)
  - Encyclopaedia Britannica Educational Corporation, 1982 (Folder 10: 14)
  - Engel, Robert, 1969 (Folder 10: 15)
  - Facts on Life Publications, 1980-1984 (Folder 10: 16)
  - Far Brook School, 1984 (Folder 10: 17)
  - Fellows, James, 1977 (Folder 10: 18)
  - Fenton Communications, Inc., 1985 (Folder 10: 19)
  - Fernbach, Linders J., 1985-1986 (Folder 10: 20)
  - Finn, Chester E., Jr., 1986 (Folder 10: 21)
  - Florence V. Burden Foundation, 1979 (Folder 10: 22)
  - Florida International University, 1984 (Folder 10: 23)
  - Flum, Joseph, 1988 (Folder 10: 24)
  - Footitt, Paul G., 1982-1984 (Folder 10: 25)
  - Ford Foundation, 1978-1987 (Folder 10: 26)
  - Franklin, John H., 1976 (Folder 10: 27)
  - Free Press, 1989 (Folder 10: 28)
  - Fromm, Hanna, 1976-1978 (Folder 10: 29)
  - Fuchs, Beverly, 1982 (Folder 10: 30)
  - Fuchs, Larry, 1987 (Folder 10: 31)
  - Gardner, John W., 1978-1983 (Folder 10: 32)
  - Gartzke, Norman, 1977 (Folder 10: 33)
  - Gehrung Associates University Relations Counselors, 1979 (Folder 10: 34)
  - German Marshall Fund, 1984 (Folder 10: 35)
  - Gewirtz, Max, 1977 (Folder 10: 36)
  - Giardino, Alfred, 1976-1977 (Folder 10: 37)
  - Gow, Kathleen M., 1980 (Folder 10: 38)
  - Guckenheimer, Julius, 1979 (Folder 10: 39)
  - Hague, John A., 1976 (Folder 10: 40)
  - Halstead, Carol P., 1981 (Folder 10: 41)
  - Hamilton College, 1982 (Folder 10: 42)
  - Harper & Row, Publishers, Inc., 1989 (Folder 10: 43)
  - Harris, Frank, 1978 (Folder 10: 44)
  - Harvard Medical School, 1990 (Folder 10: 45)
  - Harvard University, 1961-1990 (Folder 10: 46)
  - Haskins, Caryl P., 1979 (Box-folder 11: 1)
  - Havely, Sid, 1978-1979 (Folder 11: 2)
  - Heller, Amy A., 1985 (Folder 11: 3)
  - Heller, Helen, 1983 (Folder 11: 4)
  - Henderson, Douglas J., 1981 (Folder 11: 5)
  - Holm, Celeste, 1986 (Folder 11: 6)
  - Honig, Bill, 1984-1985 (Folder 11: 7)
  - Hood College, 1978-1990 (Folder 11: 8)
  - Hoover Institution on War, Revolution and Peace, 1984-1991 (Folder 11: 9)
  - Hunt, James B., Jr., 1987 (Folder 11: 10)
  - Hunter College, 1976-1985 (Folder 11: 11)
  - Independent Sector, 1985-1987 (Folder 11: 12)
  - Indiana University, 1981-1987 (Folder 11: 13)
  - INFORM, 1982-1988 (Folder 11: 14)
  - Institute for Journalism Education, 1985 (Folder 11: 15)
  - Institute of International Education, 1982 (Folder 11: 16)
  - International Council for Educational Development, 1980-1983 (Folder 11: 17)
  - James Parton and Company, Inc., 1980 (Folder 11: 18)
  - Javits, Jacob K., 1979 (Folder 11: 19)
  - Jeffers, Susan J., 1977 (Folder 11: 20)
  - Jennings, Frank G., 1969 (Folder 11: 21)
  - John Wiley & Sons, Inc., 1984 (Folder 11: 22)
  - Johns Hopkins University, 1983-1985 (Folder 11: 23)
  - Johnson Foundation, Inc., 1982-1988 (Folder 11: 24)
  - Kaplan, George B., 1977 (Folder 11: 25)
  - Kazenoff, Harry, 1980 (Folder 11: 26)
  - Kelly, Frances M., 1976 (Folder 11: 27)
  - Kelly, James A., 1985 (Folder 11: 28)
  - Kessler, Marian S., 1980-1984 (Folder 11: 29)
  - Kevles, Barbara, 1978-1979 (Folder 11: 30)
  - Kobliner, Richard, 1982 (Folder 11: 31)
  - Koch, Edward I., 1976 (Folder 11: 32)
  - Kraig, Anne B., 1983 (Folder 11: 33)
  - Krantz, Douglas E., 1976 (Folder 11: 34)
  - Landman, Gerald, 1982-1983 (Folder 11: 35)
  - Lebenger, Seymour S., 1979 (Folder 11: 36)
  - Leopold Schepp Foundation, 1984 (Folder 11: 37)
  - Levin, Henry M., 1987 (Box-folder 12: 1)
  - Lewis, Anne C., 1986 (Folder 12: 2)
  - Lewis, William S., Jr., 1977 (Folder 12: 3)
  - Literary Market Place, 1978-1980 (Folder 12: 4)
  - Machlowitz, Marilyn M., 1979 (Folder 12: 5)
  - Marcus, Ann, 1976 (Folder 12: 6)
  - Marine Biological Laboratory, 1985 (Folder 12: 7)
  - Mark, Arthur, 1977 (Folder 12: 8)
  - Markel, Lester, 1976 (Folder 12: 9)
  - Marshak, Robert E., 1977-1982 (Folder 12: 10)
  - Mattleman, Marciene S., 1984 (Folder 12: 11)
  - Maxwell, Katherine B., 1988 (Folder 12: 12)
  - McAfee, Jerry, 1983 (Folder 12: 13)
  - McClellan, Woodford, 1986 (Folder 12: 14)
  - McGraw Hill, 1975 (Folder 12: 15)
  - McGuinn, J. J., 1980 (Folder 12: 16)
  - Media History Digest, 1980 (Folder 12: 17)
  - Michigan State University, 1978-1988 (Folder 12: 18)
  - Miramonte High School, 1983 (Folder 12: 19)
  - Mobil Oil Corporation, 1985 (Folder 12: 20)
  - Mooney, Richard, 1976 (Folder 12: 21)
  - Moore, Roy L., 1979 (Folder 12: 22)
  - Moseley Associates, Inc., 1983-1985 (Folder 12: 23)
  - Mount Vernon Public Schools, 1979 (Folder 12: 24)
  - Moyers, Bill, 1981 (Folder 12: 25)
  - National Association of College Admissions Counselors, 1984 (Folder 12: 26)
  - National Association of Secondary School Principals (NASSP), 1983-1986 (Folder 12: 27)
  - National Council of Foreign Language and International Studies, 1980-1983 (Folder 12: 28)
  - National Council of Jewish Women, 1979-1980 (Folder 12: 29)
  - National Council on Measurement in Education, n.d. (Folder 12: 30)
  - National Foundation for Educational Research in England and Wales, 1988 (Folder 12: 31)
  - National Research Council, 1977 (Folder 12: 32)
  - National School Volunteer Program (NSVP), 1983 (Folder 12: 33)
  - National Science Board, 1982 (Folder 12: 34)
  - Negishi, Mitsuko, 1983 (Folder 12: 35)
  - New England Board of Higher Education, 1983 (Folder 12: 36)
  - New Frame Work Group, 1982-1983 (Folder 12: 37)
  - New York City. Board of Education, 1976-1990 (Folder 12: 38)
  - New York Public Library, 1989-1990 (Folder 12: 39)
  - New York State Association of Foreign Language Teachers, 1981 (Folder 12: 40)
  - New York University, 1976-1990 (Folder 12: 41)
  - Noah, Harold J., 1976 (Box-folder 13: 1)
  - Noble, Janie, 1984 (Folder 13: 2)
  - North Carolina School of Science and Mathematics, 1980 (Folder 13: 3)
  - Nunn, Sam, 1987 (Folder 13: 4)
  - Old College, 1979-1982 (Folder 13: 5)
  - Open Court Publishing Company, 1978-1985 (Folder 13: 6)
  - Parade Publications, Inc., 1990 (Folder 13: 7)
  - Parents' Magazine and Better Homemaking, 1960-1961 (Folder 13: 8)
  - Pepper, Gay S., 1985 (Folder 13: 9)
  - Perelman, Lewis J., 1985 (Folder 13: 10)
  - Pew Charitable Trust, 1987 (Folder 13: 11)
  - Pforzheimer, Carl H., III, 1981 (Folder 13: 12)
  - Poets and Writers, Inc., 1977-1978 (Folder 13: 13)
  - Power, Sarah Goddard, 1977 (Folder 13: 14)
  - Pratt, John W., Mrs., 1977 (Folder 13: 15)
  - Probber, Jonathan, 1985 (Folder 13: 16)
  - Procter and Gamble Company, 1987 (Folder 13: 17)
  - Provost, Dan, 1977 (Folder 13: 18)
  - Public Interest Public Relations (PIPR), 1982 (Folder 13: 19)
  - RAND Corporation, 1979 (Folder 13: 20)
  - Randall, Ruth E., 1988 (Folder 13: 21)
  - Red, Virginia, S., 1988 (Folder 13: 22)
  - Reed, Linda A., 1984 (Folder 13: 23)
  - RFE/RL, inc., 1977 (Folder 13: 24)
  - Rhodes, Frank H. T., 1988 (Folder 13: 25)
  - Richardson, John, Jr., 1976 (Folder 13: 26)
  - Rockefeller, John D., III, Mrs., 1977 (Folder 13: 27)
  - Rosenfield, Nancy, 1976 (Folder 13: 28)
  - Rosenthal, Irving, 1984-1989 (Folder 13: 29)
  - Rosovsky, Isador, 1979 (Folder 13: 30)
  - Rothwell, Bruce, 1979 (Folder 13: 31)
  - Russell Sage Foundation, 1982 (Folder 13: 32)
  - Rutenber, Ralph D., 1977 (Folder 13: 33)
  - Rutgers University, 1976-1983 (Folder 13: 34)
  - Saltzman, Henry, 1976 (Folder 13: 35)
  - Saturday Review, 1978-1980 (Folder 13: 36)
  - SBS Associates, Inc., 1989 (Folder 13: 37)
  - Schmidt, Frances, 1963 (Folder 13: 38)
  - Science Museum of Long Island, 1984 (Folder 13: 39)
  - Search for Solutions, 1985 (Folder 13: 40)
  - Seattle Times, 1977 (Folder 13: 41)
  - Seely, David S., 1982-1983 (Folder 13: 42)
  - Segal, Martin E., 1987 (Folder 13: 43)
  - Seven Springs Center, 1981-1982 (Folder 13: 44)
  - Sharr, Mimi, 1980 (Folder 13: 45)
  - Silberman, Arlene, 1987 (Folder 13: 46)
  - Simmons, Adele, 1988 (Folder 13: 47)
  - Simon, Paul, 1984-1990 (Folder 13: 48)
  - Smith Richardson Foundation, Inc., 1981 (Folder 13: 49)
  - Stanford University, 1977-1989 (Folder 13: 50)
  - Stanford University. Libraries, 1975-1989 (Box-folder 14: 1)
  - State University College of Arts and Science, Genesco, New York, 1980 (Folder 14: 2)
  - State University of New York at Albany, 1978-1989 (Folder 14: 3)
  - State University of New York at Buffalo, 1988? (Folder 14: 4)
  - Stein, Morris I., 1985 (Folder 14: 5)
  - Steiner, B. Franklin, 1964 (Folder 14: 6)
  - Stern, Philip M., 1983 (Folder 14: 7)
  - Students Association of the State University of New York, Inc., 1982 (Folder 14: 8)
  - Sturgeon, Robert, 1985 (Folder 14: 9)
  - Sulzberger, Arthur Hays, Mrs., 1976-1986 (Folder 14: 10)
  - Susquehanna University, 1977-1984 (Folder 14: 11)
  - Sutphen, Preston L., Jr., Mrs., 1987 (Folder 14: 12)
  - Syracuse University, 1984 (Folder 14: 13)
  - Tankel, Sam, 1955-1985 (Folder 14: 14)
  - Tobin, Catherine, 1985 (Folder 14: 15)
  - Tufts University, 1982 (Folder 14: 16)
  - Ubel, Earl, 1988. (Folder 14: 17)
    Includes a letter to Doris R. Field, 1989
  - United Nations University, 1978-1987 (Folder 14: 18)
  - United States. Congress. House of Representatives, 1976-1989 (Folder 14: 19)
  - United States. Dept. of Education, 1981-1984 (Folder 14: 20)
  - United States. Dept. of Energy, 1989 (Folder 14: 21)
  - United States. General Accounting Office, 1983 (Folder 14: 22)
  - United States. Dept. of Health, Education, and Welfare, 1978 (Folder 14: 23)
  - United States. Dept. of Health and Human Services, 1990 (Folder 14: 24)
  - United States. Senate, 1983 (Folder 14: 25)
  - United States-Japan Foundation, 1983 (Folder 14: 26)
  - University of Akron, Ohio, 1980 (Folder 14: 27)
  - University of California, Berkeley, 1967-1990 (Folder 14: 28)
  - University of California, Los Angeles, 1979-1990 (Folder 14: 29)
  - University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign, 1984 (Folder 14: 30)
  - University of South Florida. College of Education, 1983-1987 (Folder 14: 31)
  - University of Washington, 1986 (Folder 14: 32)
  - Viederman, Stephen, 1976-1986 (Folder 14: 33)
  - Wadsworth, Deborah, 1981-1982 (Folder 14: 34)
  - Washington University, St. Louis, 1980-1986 (Folder 14: 35)